# **Nicole Kauffman**

Multimedia Specialist
TS/SCI with FSP

# Personal Info

Address 18830 Farnham Court Leesburg, VA 20176

Phone Number 703-980-1396

Email nkauff27@gmail.com

# **Technical Skills**

Photoshop PowerPoint

Illustrator Word
InDesign Excel

After Effects Visual Studio

Dreamweaver Joomla

XD HTML/CSS

Acrobat JavaScript

# **Design Skills**

**Print Design** 

**UX/UI** Design

**Typography** 

**Brand & Identity Design** 

**Data Visualization** 

**Information Graphics** 

Illustration

**Photo Retouching/Manipulation** 

**Animation** 

**Desktop Publishing** 

**Photography** 

Highly creative and motivated multi-media designer with thirteen years of experience working with government entities in a creative lead role, while producing a range of professional graphic and design elements to include reports, briefings, illustrations, images, logos, animations, and websites.

### **Employment History**

#### 2019 to Present, Multimedia Specialist, NextPoint Group, Dulles, VA

Using a variety of multimedia knowledge, skills, and abilities to design and develop sophisticated products per client request. Responsible for multimedia project team leadership, customer relations, product research and content development, programming, and interface design. Design products in support of multimedia presentations including but not limited to posters, infographics, video design, animations, Power Points, and web-based products using the Joomla platform.

#### 2014 to 2019, Sr. Graphic Designer Associate, Booz Allen Hamilton, Mclean, VA

- Interacted with Intelligence Community officers to design and develop complex and professional graphics and illustrations for use in technical materials, manuals, and publications from concept to completion.
- Determined style, technique, and medium best suited for production and created a workflow for graphic requests and communicated this process to various groups requiring design support.
- Worked meticulously with officers to ensure appropriate material were being conveyed and that the end user can understand the material presented through appropriate design techniques.
- Rebranded various offices to include new logos, letterheads, brochures, PowerPoint presentations, and websites.

# 2014, Project Engineer, Perspecta, Chantilly, VA

- Acted as primary POC for selected projects and participated in technical exchange meetings, control gate board and reviews.
- Utilized graphic design skills by creating posters and videos detailing mission specific projects.

#### 2011 to 2014, Senior Graphic Designer, Perspecta, McLean, VA

- Conducted several manual facial comparative analyses on figures-of-interests to national security by using digital programs to enhance imagery and raise valuable identifying features.
- Provided guidance to less experienced designers and maintained current knowledge of relevant technology as assigned.
- Acted as a focal point for visual information activities and responsible for the design and development of a wide variety visual materials.
- Planned the foundational framework of creating and documenting artificial personas and trained staff on how to create these composites. From this, the IC group experienced a significant increase in the demand for these personas from various government branches which eventually lead to new hires in the group.
- Assisted in the development of recruitment tests and questionnaires to hire additional designers for the team.
- Communicated with groups and assisted in setting up meetings to consult on project expectations, processes, and timelines.
- Co-lead a two-week mission overseas with five staffers. Involved in the collection of over ten thousand images in four countries that would be documented and later used

- Planned the foundational framework of creating and documenting artificial personas and trained staff on how to create these composites. From this, the group experienced a significant increase in the demand for these personas from various government branches which eventually lead to new hires.
- Assisted in the development of recruitment tests and questionnaires to hire additional designers for the team.
- Communicated with groups and assisted in setting up meetings to consult on project expectations, processes, and timelines.
- Co-lead a two-week mission overseas with five staffers. Involved in the collection of over ten thousand images in four countries that would be documented and later used for customer tasking.
- Co-planned, developed, and lead a large staffer group to a customer site for one week where we set up, documented, and photographed over fifteen thousand images of various activities for future projects.

# 2010 to 2011, Graphic Designer, Raytheon-Telemus, McLean, VA

- Supported various development efforts from concept through completion and worked directly with division chiefs, branch managers, team leads, and subject matter experts.
- Created quick turnaround products directed towards directors and POTUS.
- Provided graphics and production expertise to peers and department colleagues leading to an increase in work production and the hiring of additional graphic designers

#### **Education**

- Career Foundry Advanced UX/UI Design Expected Completion Date April 2022
- General Assembly JavaScript Development Certificate February 2021
- Masters Certificate in Human Computer Interaction, Iowa State University, Des Moines, IA 2017
- Masters Certificate in Visual Communications, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD 2005
- Bachelor of Science, Biology, Stevenson University, Baltimore, MD 2001

# **Training**

- NSA Facial Analysis Training, Ft. Meade, Maryland, 2013
- DOD Introduction to Electronic Identity and Cyber Security Implications of PEDS, Elkridge, Maryland, 2013
- Forensic Imaging Training, Tampa, Florida, 2012
- Digital Photography Workshop, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 2012
- FOTOfusion 2012 Training, Palm Beach, Florida, 2012